#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a well-rounded Python developer with over 5 years of experience in data science and web development teams. I believe in building things right, building the right things, and working in a sustainable way. That means caring about code quality and testing, releasing small and iterating, practising open communication and always reflecting on my processes. Looking for a new position where I can make a difference.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

OCTOBER 2018 - PRESENT

# Senior Software Engineer at Threads Styling, London

Building client-facing solutions and internal integrations for a chatbased luxury shopping platform.

- Built support for new payment methods
- Automated uploading of payment receipts to Google Drive
- Productionized older code by writing tests before refactoring, CI integration and using Terraform to deploy to AWS

March 2017 - August 2018

## Senior Software Engineer at siroop, Zürich

Worked in the data science and the web development team of a Swiss e-commerce platform with thousands of sales every day.

#### Full Stack Web development

- Built critical features from scratch (voucher and promotion support, custom brand pages, integration of analytics tracking) using Diango, Flask and RESTful services
- Extended existing functionality (product pages, CMS service and payment system) practising TDD and pair programming
- Optimized test running time, local deployments with dockercompose and other aspects of the day to day development process
- Updated and deployed new AWS infrastructure (lambdas, Kinesis stream, DynamoDB) using Terraform
- Participated and led agile ceremonies (stand-ups, retrospectives)
- Acted as deputy team lead for a team of 7 and mentored more junior engineers

#### **Data Engineering**

- Worked closely with data scientists to build a tool library
- Introduced and set up airflow as a pipeline manager for the recurring jobs
- Introduced and set up databricks as a development environment
- Did troubleshooting for all scaling and cluster issues the data scientists faced (pySpark and pandas)
- Build a system out of AWS components to generate personalized product recommendations



Ariadni-Karolina Alexiou
 17 Bessemer Place, London SE
 +44 73 83 001 288

□ carolinegr@gmail.com

http://www.github.com/carolinux

#### WORK EXPERIENCE CONTD.

November 2015 - February 2017

# Lead Data Engineer at Tracktics GmbH, Zürich

Responsible for overseeing the extracting of insights from GPS and sensor data, collected from a tracker worn by football players in the field.

- Built a data pipeline based on celery to automatically process the raw data (various stages, eg: a MATLAB program developed by domain experts in sensor data, Jupyter notebooks and python modules, chained together)
- Designed and oversaw the collection of test data to evaluate our algorithms
- Built evaluation into the data pipeline (in a way that externals could use it, and internals could easily create new report templates for new metrics)
- Built a library of common functionality together with the data scientists and mentored junior engineers

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2015

# Software Engineer at Teralytics AG, Zürich

Worked as a software engineer, extracting insights from mobile phone data and supporting my colleagues to do so.

- Created data pipelines to go from raw data to automatically updating web dashboards (using luigi)
- Created interactive visualizations of geospatial data (using PostGIS, d3, QGIS)
- Built a library to unify access to all the different data sources from telco providers (in Scala)

# SELECTED CONFERENCES AND ARTICLES

2017 Speaker at PyData Berlin conference:
Patterns for Collaboration between Data Scientists
and Software Engineers
video | article

2016 Published reflections on the future of Data Pipelines and the future of Python for Data Science

2015 Tutorial with Python code snippets: Exploring a UFO sightings dataset

2015 Article: Common mistakes with Python and Big Data

on Mall Analytics (from prototype to product)

2015 Workshop on visualizing geotemporal data QGIS user & dev conference (plugin co-authored)

2014 Presented published paper at
 Very Large Databases Conference 2014
 2014 Speaker at PyData Berlin conference

#### **EDUCATION**

2011 - 2013 **Master of Science** 

COMPUTER SCIENCE ETH Zürich

GPA: 5.5/6 (also received scholarship)

2007 - 2011 Bachelor of Science

COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Athens

GPA: 9.3/10 - Top graduate in fall 2011

### SELECTED FREELANCE OR OTHER WORK

## Node Developer for SignedBlock, Athens

Extended and dockerized a program for live collection of data from the cryptocurrency market.

#### QGIS Plugin Developer for OpenGis.ch, Zürich

Responsible for developing Python plugins for geospatial data management.

#### Python and Data Engineering Tutor, online

Micro-consulting via codementor.io on several data science/engineering projects.

#### Mentor at Andela, online

Mentored junior programmers in Python, testing and programming patterns to prepare them for working remotely.

#### Data Consultant for New Incentives, Zürich

Created a data pipeline in Scala to sync data daily across mobile devices and Google spreadsheets.

#### Software Engineering Intern, Google Zürich

Migrated a feature of Youtube Analytics to the new backend.

#### LANGUAGES

English, German and Spanish in full professional capacity. Greek as mother tongue, some French.

#### Personal Interests

Painting (have some professional training), Social Science, Travelling. I have combined my thinking/practice as a programmer with those of being an artist to create a Drawing for Techies Workshop, which I have run multiple times in Switzerland, Germany and the UK.